Kevin Workman

kevinaworkman@gmail.com June 2022

By day I'm a software engineer at Google. By night I'm an adjunct professor at Millersville University. By later night I post tutorials to HappyCoding.io! I'm especially interested in the intersection of code, creativity, and education.

Education / Open Source Experience

Millersville University - Adjunct Professor

January 2022 - Present

- Currently teaching <u>Intro to Web Development</u>.
- Developed a project-based curriculum focusing on creativity.
- Created videos and tutorials for students to work through asynchronously.
- Held weekly virtual classes where students share their work.

Google Software Product Sprint - Curriculum Lead

February 2017 - Present

- <u>SPS</u> (formerly CodeU) is a Google outreach program designed to encourage promising undergraduate students to (re)apply to Google. Students work in groups alongside a Google advisor over 8 weeks on a technical project.
- I wrote SPS's <u>technical curriculum</u>, which uses project-based walkthroughs to guide students through creating a personally meaningful web app using Google Cloud libraries, with student engagement as the main goal.
- So far, over 2000 people have worked through the SPS curriculum.
- As a team advisor, I've directly mentored 35 students in 10 SPS sessions.

Happy Coding — Nerd

June 2016 - Present

- I post tutorials, examples, and other nerdiness at <u>HappyCoding.io</u>.
- Content includes p5.js, Processing, Java (core and EE), JavaScript, HTML, Google Cloud, Android, and libGDX. (133 tutorials + 170 examples so far!)
- Used as the "textbook" for my Intro to Web Dev course and for University of Chicago's <u>CS 11111</u> course.

Processing / p5.js - Open Source Contributor

August 2011 - Present

- Currently the all-time top answerer of Stack Overflow questions tagged with the <u>processing</u>, <u>p5.js</u>, and <u>processing.js</u> tags.
- Taught sessions at <u>CC Fest</u> in SF and LA including the power and beauty of random, image processing, and <u>sp00ky halloween sketches</u>.

Work Experience

- I'm currently a SWE on the engEDU platform team, developing the systems used for internal trainings, <u>CS First</u>, and <u>Applied Digital Skills</u>.
- Previously I was a tech lead for a team in <u>Google My Business</u>, where I led several feature launches used by millions of users, e.g. attributes, descriptions, opening dates, place actions, and temporary closures.
- I've advocated for building the ownership and expertise of my peers, focusing on long-term velocity rather than short-term gain, improving our documentation, and caring more about user and operator happiness rather than shallow engagement metrics.

Get More Math, Remote — Software Engineer

January 2016 - November 2016 (Contractor)

- Get More Math is an educational software suite that gives students individualized math problems based on where they need the most practice.
- Developed new procedural generators based on teacher requests.

Vencore, McLean Virginia — Software Engineer

February 2009 - November 2016

- Worked as a contractor for the <u>Center for Advanced Aviation System</u>
 <u>Development</u>, which is an FFRDC that develops prototypes for the FAA.
- Created frontends, "middle ends", and visualizations used by air traffic control prototype research.
- Development was very conversation-based. A researcher gets an idea for a new algorithm or display, and I rapidly develop a proof of concept and then we iterate together, aka <u>evolutionary prototyping</u>.

Fducation

George Mason University, Virginia — MS in Computer Science

2011 - 2015

- Obtained a master's degree in Computer Science while working full time.
- Cool projects include: ant colony optimization, evolutionary mazes, predicting Ludum Dare scores, developing an AR Android game, and building an "artistic" drawing robot (full disclosure: it wasn't very artistic).

Millersville University, Pennsylvania — BS in Computer Science

2004 - 2008

- Helped create and implement a new undergraduate robotics course.
- Worked as tech support at the university's help desk, as an undergraduate researcher, and as the assistant system admin in the CS department.
- Other activities included tutoring, speaking at conferences, running CS camps, and way more independent studies than was strictly necessary.
- Interned at the <u>National Institute of Standards and Technology</u>.

References

References are available upon request. 😺